Code review is the skill that can
take your hacking to the next level,
especially when you know in which software
to look for bugs. And today I'm joined by
Shubs who knows this better than
anyone else. Enjoy the interview.
Hello Shubs, thank you so much for joining
me today to talk about bug bounty and your
your hacking tips. For those of you who don't know
you, how did you start with hacking? What's your
background? Yeah sure, so I started hacking when
I was maybe 12-13 years old. One of the things
that drew me into hacking was just because my dad
had bought us a computer and my brother and I we
used to play online games together. But my brother
used to always beat me at these games which really
sucked and I really wanted to to get either good
enough at these games or figure out a way to beat
my brother. So I got into game hacking initially.
I looked into making things like undetectable
cheat engines to bypass anti-game cheat detection
and also looked into things like aim bots and
things like that for the different online
games that we were playing. When I was about
13 I also realized that there's this field of web
application security and that was really something
that I only realized after connecting with people
in the game hacking scene. And from there I was
able to really develop a passion and interest in
web application security specifically. And that
passion and interest has basically come through
all the way until now. That's something that I've
heavily specialized in. That's something that
I spend almost all my time in when it comes to
information security. And yeah basically from game
hacking and getting into web application security,
I eventually got into bug bounties. But the
story is essentially that when I was around
14 years old I was working at Hungry Jack's,
which is the equivalent of Burger King in
other countries. I was making like $6.50 an
hour, which isn't really a lot of money to
be making but at the time you know I come from an
immigrant family, we didn't have that much money,
it was still an incredible opportunity for
me. But I was also doing bug bounties as
much as I could at the time. And at this time
there was no HackerOne or BugCrowd really,
maybe they were just getting started off. But
there was Microsoft and PayPal's bug bounty.
And I was submitting bugs to PayPal, a lot of the
bugs had almost no security impact. However one
day I came across a server-side request forgery
bug that affected BillMeLater, which is one of
PayPal's acquisitions. And at this time PayPal was
running their own bug bounty, it was not managed
by any platform or anything like that. And I
submitted it and they paid $1.5k USD. At the
time I had been working at Hungry Jack's for eight
months and I'd only made like $800 Australian.
So when I got that bug bounty I basically
never showed up to Hungry Jack's again.
Did you literally the same day? Yes, literally I
never showed up to Hungry Jack's again. Because
it was very difficult work and it was very hard
work and making $6.50 an hour, it was not really
worth it when I could just spend time focusing
on improving my skills in application security
and specifically finding vulnerabilities for bug
bounties. So along the way I participated in a
lot of different bug bounties initially, just for
the Hall of Fame initially, but eventually I got
into the bug bounty platforms like HackerOne and
BugCrowd. And since then I've just been focusing
on high-paying bug bounties. For how long did
you then stay doing bug bounty for full-time?
Yes, I was still in school at that time so I was
still I guess balancing school work and doing bug
bounty work. But it was something that I did
pretty consistently. I didn't make that much
money to be honest. In the first couple years
of my bug bounty journey I don't think I made
anything close to what I've been making in the
last few years in the bug bounty scene. But I was
balancing obviously my high school work and trying
to get into university and things like that. But
full-time I've only done bug bounty while I was
living in Europe, when I was living in Poland in
Krakow. So I did full-time bug bounty for around
a year when I was living in Europe. But yeah,
along the way I mean I had a lot of opportunities
here in Australia which I'm very grateful for.
When I was 17 and I had finished high school I had
sent an email to all of the pen test consultancies
in my city and I'd asked them whether or not they
would be willing to accept an intern. And I think
the fact that I had submitted to a lot of bug
bounty programs really helped with that cold
email outreach. And one of the security firms
in Australia did come back to me and said that
they'd be interested in doing an interview. I'd
passed that interview and I was very happy to I'd
passed that interview and then I joined as
an intern. Unfortunately it was a unpaid
internship so I didn't get paid anything
but I worked there for around six months
and I learned as much as I could about
consulting and pen testing and all of that.
And that was a very invaluable experience for me
at 17 years old. After that I worked at Atlassian
as a contractor where I found one security
issue a day for 30 days. And then I worked
at Ernst & Young as a consultant working
in basically any security related projects.
And I was probably around 18 at that time. And
finally I ended up working at Bishop Fox which was
a US company that focuses on offensive security
consulting. And I was there for two years ending
up as a senior security consultant. After that
I then co-founded my company that I have now.
What were your favorite places in Krakow? Because
for those of you who don't know right now I'm in
Poland, I'm in Krakow which is exactly the city
that Szabz mentioned. Szabz in Australia we have
10 hour time difference so we are pretty
much as far from each other as we can be
but turned out that he lived in the city that
I'm living now so we are your favorite places?
In Krakow I don't remember the names exactly but
there was a place that Julia used to always take
us to where they had all these different types
of vodka shots. There was like a few of them in
Krakow city. I forget the exact name but probably
Pijalnia Wódki i Piwa on the Szabzka street. Yeah,
yeah that's probably it. There's also a place
called Multi Kulti which is yeah it's got all
types of different beers like maybe 30 beers
on tap or something which is incredible and
yeah really nice spot to just hang out maybe
just go with a few friends to the smoking area
drink some beers have a few cigarettes you know
that's definitely one of the areas that I spent
a lot of time at and yeah I guess generally
with Krakow it was just you know I love the
scenery of Krakow I loved walking in the park
love seeing all the beautiful green trees and
going to the cafe every morning and going to
all these different bars and the nightlife was
phenomenal the people were quite good as
well so it was a great experience I mean
I don't I definitely look back on those
memories fondly but I think there was a
bit too much drinking going on to remember
all the names of the places that I went to.
Yeah, yeah but it's great also I've just been
before this podcast half an hour in the park
very very sunny day very green to chill out and
I really really like it. Now at Assetnote do you
still do hacking or do you do you do something
else? Yeah, yeah I still do hacking so at the
moment I'm managing our security research team
so we have a team of three people excluding me so
it's four people total and basically we take apart
enterprise software we find zero days in them and
we ultimately do this to find vulnerabilities that
we can check for in our platform inside Assetnote
and all of our customers they get a basically an
advanced notification of any of these zero days
that affect their infrastructure. The really good
news is that because we have so many customers
at Assetnote we can use that information
and that data that we have to make really
informed decisions about which technologies
we should go after. We only really go after
technologies that are being ran by our customers
so if we notice that a customer is running xyz
enterprise product we will you know obtain a
copy of that reverse engineer it find zero days
and add it to our platform so it is something
that we actively do for all of our customers
and yeah these days at Assetnote I mean it's a
mix between I mean it's a mix between a lot of
things as a co-founder I wear a lot of hats I do a
lot of customer support I do a lot of engineering
and I do a lot of security research so those are
the three main things that I focus on at Assetnote
and really I'm not afraid to do anything necessary
to move the business forward so you know some days
I might be doing six hours of customer support
work and that's fine like I'm happy to do that
that's no big deal I think that by me being
able to provide this information and support
to our customers there's not that many products
that are that are doing that sort of work so
it does differentiate us I think greatly from
our competitors that you know even the CTO is
doing support work Which activities are your
favorite? Which is what my favorite sorry?
Which activities that you mentioned are your
favorite? Definitely security research I mean
that's by far my favorite I do a lot of security
research with our team and you know managing a
security research team also is quite interesting
because not only do you have to figure out the
targets for the team to go after you also have to
do a lot of the work to set up everything in a way
that minimizes the amount of time taken for the
team to get to get started with this sort of stuff
so often I am finding myself setting up enterprise
software and I guess getting everything ready but
I do also spend a lot of time actually working
with my team finding the vulnerabilities as well
what I've found is with adding more people
to the security research team at Assetnote
the chances and likelihood of exploitation of
harder to exploit issues has gone down because of
the collaboration element between us and you know
things that I would typically be stuck on in the
past has been things that we've been able to solve
recently due to the collaboration element that we
have and that's been really really good and I've
also noticed that you know a lot of the people
that we've hired in our security research team
they have different personalities perspectives
viewpoints methodologies that ultimately are
all complementing each other I mean for me I
personally tend to think very quickly and get
through things as quickly as possible but we
also have people on our team that are really
good at that and do take a lot of time to go
through each individual controller or whatever is
being mapped to an externally routable endpoint so
I'm seeing that the methodologies that we have
have a lot of benefit but yeah ultimately I do
love security research that is my favorite thing
how do you split projects between people in the
team does do you all work on the same project or
do you does do you all work on the same project
or is it individual and then you ask someone for
help how does it work it's it's quite dynamic so I
mean at Assetnote we we see our security research
team functioning in basically two major ways one
is the proactive security research and the second
is the reactive security research so for us you
know if anything drops on the internet if there's
a vulnerability in xyz product and there's no POC
our security research team is responsible in in
order to figure out what the POC is so they will
have to download the software reverse engineer
it find the POC and this also goes for all sorts
of other vulnerabilities that are dropping on the
internet so if there are things that are dropping
on the internet our security research team is
responsible for investigating it and adding a
check to our to our platform but we also have
the reactive side now the sorry the proactive
side and the proactive side is where we go out and
we actually do security research ourselves and do
original security research the the to answer your
question when it comes to splitting up of the team
it really depends on what the priorities
are sometimes we have a lot of work from
the reactive side that requires a full resource
to be focused on that reactive work so that they
will be doing that work and not the proactive work
but sometimes we can work together as a team we
do tend to give entire projects to an individual
so let's say for example we are auditing moodle
for example that would be assigned to a single
security researcher here at asset note and if
they do find anything interesting or anything they
want help with then we're happy to collaborate and
work with them at any given moment in time
but usually one person is leading the audit
okay and that's you kind of mentioned it because
i've noticed from a lot of your blog posts you
mentioned i don't know recently oracle opera
software that's used in millions of hotels
which i've never heard about and i wanted to to
ask how you choose your targets but i i guess
you just look at the software your customers use
that's right so it's a mix between two things we
look at this the software that our customer uses
but we also look at any popular software basically
um any anything that is popular enough that maybe
a future customer might use is something that's
valuable to us so it's not necessarily that our
customer has to absolutely be running it for us
to to do security research on but if there is
a software product um some enterprise product
that has a lot of popularity or it is being used
across many different segments in industries we
will definitely spend the time on it because one
of the benefits for that is you know we we demo
our product um pretty much on the attack surface
of any prospect so if someone comes to us and they
want to buy us and we're demoing on their attack
surface we're scanning their attack surface so
um finding zero days in popular products
generally is uh basically the goal uh for
our security research team on top of any products
that our customers are using um oracle opera is
something that was actually found as a result of a
live hacking event that was ran by bug crowd last
year and they had a very famous resort in scope
a huge us resort which had exposed oracle opera
externally to the internet so that was something
that we we looked at because of that specifically
but we ended up finding a few customers that had
oracle opera exposed on the external internet as
well so one of the things that i love about what
i do at asset node and the bug bounty world is a
lot of the things that i'm doing is basically two
birds with one stone any security research that i
do has benefits from the asset note perspective
and also from the bug bounty perspective and
vice versa basically any any research i do on the
bug bounty side has benefits to asset so that's
something that that for me has been really um
uh really been i've really been able to maximize
my output with just doing uh zero day research
when you find the zero day apart from any adding
it to to a detection or whatever do you also
monetize it in public bug bounty programs yeah
we do so we actually we have a we have a program
internally at asset node which is basically the
bug bounty bonus program so this is something
that we currently offer our employees where
if you are doing research during worked hours
and work time using our resources and things
like that and you find a zero day that affects a
bunch of bug bounty programs we will put it into
a pool of money which gets split up as a bonus at
the end of the year between the research team so
really for us we've seen some really big bonuses
in the last few years as a result of our team
finding zero days in many various popular products
which all goes towards this bug bounty bonus pool
so it gets split evenly there's no like uh special
treatment for anyone on the team and it's a it's a
great incentive for our researchers to stay and
stick around at asset node yeah yeah it sounds
really cool and also the even split probably helps
you avoid any conflicts inside because if it's
uneven split it's always someone has problems with
it yeah how did your hacking style change from
when you were only doing bug bounty to now when
you focus on the security research of zero days
um yeah it's changed a lot actually um so when
i was just doing bug bounty and i wasn't doing
source code analysis i found that i was spending
a lot of time basically doing a lot of menial
manual work that i didn't enjoy as much for
me now source code analysis always presents
a very specific challenge to me that that i know
that there's more work to be done to be better at
whereas the work that i was doing in manual
bug bounty hunting it often felt like it was
not predictable it wasn't deterministic
it was something that required a lot of
effort and sometimes didn't lead to that much
outcome whereas now being more strategic about
the targets that i pick and being more strategic
about how i break into something through security
research is something that's led to an immense
amount of bounties over the last couple years
and as i said earlier like with security
research i can knock two birds with one
stone and that's that's basically why i do it
so much these days but yeah my hacking style
um really one of the things that's probably the
most obvious thing to me is that i focused a lot
on client-side security in my first few years of
bug bounty hunting like immensely like i was on
top of all the client-side security controls i was
doing a lot of work with different techniques with
client-side security stuff and then eventually i
realized that no i don't really want to get these
lower end bug bounties anymore and i don't want to
spend this much time reporting on things that have
not as much security impact as i think they should
like i want to focus on the things that will
actually compromise the target that will actually
lead to a full compromise and after that point i
think i've only exclusively focused on server-side
issues i would say in the last couple years i mean
i'm still happy to report an xss or whatever but
it doesn't excite me as much unfortunately like
it's not something that i get super excited about
doing client-side security work so these days
i've been focusing mainly on server-side
security issues and it's something that
i think that it's like a specialization
within a specialization kind of thing
it's not as if i'm not aware of all the
client-side security techniques but i'm definitely
not as good as some of the bug bounty hunters and
client-side security work that they are today but
it's the server-side security work that i have
really honed and really become a lot better at
what if the software your clients are using is not
open source yeah so i've got multiple different
techniques to discover software that's not open
source i mean there's you know one i can look at
it on docker hub if i can find someone that's
spun up a docker image that has that software
i can look for trials if that's possible usually
isn't always possible i can look at github to see
whether or not someone has put up any amount of
code that that resembles that software or i can
look at whether or not i can find s3 urls that
have that software ova files things like that
i also look at amazon marketplace and azure
marketplace which often have software that's
delivered as a pay-as-you-go sort of solution i
also look at community amis on amazon which often
contain a bunch of different amis maybe related to
the software you're looking for and yeah i think
lastly and this is the one that i hate doing is
actually contacting the sales team and asking them
for a trial but that that is something that you
have to do sometimes in order to get that software
okay so when you already have the software
how does your first hour of hacking look like
my first hour of hacking looks like basically
understanding what the software is written
in well actually to be honest the first hour
is usually spent on setting that software up
and this this is something that yeah this
is something that every security researcher
has has to deal with it's not a pretty
process it's actually a huge deterrent
not many people enjoy doing this i don't
enjoy doing it but you have to do it
sometimes setting up the software can take a lot
longer than even the first hour if you try and set
up any complex oracle software it will take you
maybe days to set it up properly so i really do
feel for the sys admins that set up this software
within enterprises it is difficult and boring work
but by the way after i've set up the software
in the first hour i spend my time understanding
exactly what software is running on the system
and understanding how it maps back to the to the
to the executables or the jar files or to the code
or whatever it may be i pull down all of that from
the system i may have to disassemble or decompile
it and then after i do that i try and understand
all of the things that may be routable from a
pre-authentication perspective that's the first
step for me usually and and just want to clarify i
mean at asset note we don't really care that much
for post authentication bugs that's not something
that we're very much so interested in where we're
interested in pre-authentication bugs here at
asset note that's what our focus is we're looking
for pre-authentication critical bugs as our
primary focus okay so you always want to run the
software to which you're auditing you never just
look at the code preferably preferably you always
want to run the software if possible now sometimes
this isn't possible like the oracle opera work
that we did we did not run that software because
it would have taken an immense amount of time to
set it up and also for the oracle opera software
there were multiple zip files that were corrupt so
we even if we wanted to run the software it would
be wouldn't have been possible but where possible
we will always try and run the software because
we want dynamic debugging we want to be able to
debug the software you know in real time we want
to be able to see all the different variables on
the stack all the different threads and we want
to be able to manipulate that as we're as we're
testing the application we want to be able
to set break points in order to step through
different parts of code to understand exactly
what is happening when we send a request and
this is incredibly important because if you don't
do this dynamic debugging component sometimes you
have to rely on your guesses and instinct which
honestly is not that good in complex software
there's just so much going on there's
just you know there's just so much going
on that you you need to have more certainty
around what is going on behind the scenes
what tools are you using for this yeah so for dot
net for dot net i use rider which is a jetbrains
product and that has been really excellent for
debugging dot net projects that's something that
i highly recommend anyone who's doing dot
network to use and for java i use intelliJ
i think intelliJ has also a feature to debug
compiled jar files did you try it out in
practice yeah so you intelliJ has a bunch of
different ways of being able to debug things
but yeah you can you can do that as well
typically i like loading up everything in
source into the into intelliJ and getting
it mapped to the java debug port and then
attaching to the process and things like that
so i mean that's that's all there's so many ways
of debugging i know that some people prefer
using eclipse as well for java debugging but
personally i've found that intelliJ has been
better to use from a debugging perspective
one of the things i've also heard recently was
that codeql can now run on c sharp without having
to compile the c sharp so i haven't used that
yet but that that is very interesting to me
speaking of of codeql do you use any tools
to catch low-hanging fruit like samgrep or
codeql scanner yeah i so i don't use codeql that
much it's something that i'd love to expand my
knowledge on and start using a bit more frequently
but i use samgrep a lot so i've i've written a few
custom samgrep rules for certain things i've also
looked at some other samgrep rules like i think
one of the ones i've looked at is eltems custom
samgrep rules which they have a custom they have
some custom java rules and some other rules there
but yeah i i i think that samgrep is an incredibly
valuable tool when it comes to finding this this
low-hanging fruit although i will say that samgrep
often does not always get things right it does
require a lot of human i guess it does require a
little bit more of a investigation to understand
whether or not samgrep is actually truly correct
about what it's found but i mean as a tool that
assists me in source code auditing i find it very
valuable okay and when you get to manually
auditing the code how do you do this do you
look at at by functionality by functionality
basis or do you find sinks how do you do it
yes i i usually focus on a list of known functions
within any language that i know will lead to some
sort of security issue so if it's um dot net or
java or whatever i have a list of things that i
grep for that i look for um specifically to try
and investigate whether or not they're reachable
but as i said earlier one of the things that
we focus on um in the first hour of getting
the software set up is finding all of the routes
that are pre-authentication and looking at these
routes you can often at a glance figure out what
these functionalities may mean or may be wanting
to do i mean if you have a controller that's like
called download or something that certainly sounds
like it's uh it's interesting and worthwhile for
you to investigate further um but yeah i i think
my testing methodology is a bit bit dynamic i
mean i have adhd so i think that i jump around
a lot from place to place i don't think that i
am as methodological as most people that have a
checklist or anything like that um i tend to rely
a lot on gut instinct as well and that's just from
that's just being developed through doing a lot
of source code auditing over the years i mean even
professionally when i was working at bishop fox i
was doing source code auditing as well there for a
lot of different customers in different industries
and different languages but yeah i think the more
i source code audit the better i tend to become at
finding things quicker when new researchers come
to to work with you what are the mistakes you see
them doing at the beginning um well i think that
uh one of the big mistakes can often be giving
up on a target too early so one of the things
that i've seen is you know like a researcher will
say i've audited it there's no security issues
and this is like maybe two days after you've
assigned them the project or something right and
honestly for a lot of the really large
enterprise software that we're looking at
um it's a very grueling process and it requires
a lot of boring things to be done before you
find that gold or those gems and sometimes
it's a matter of uncovering attack surface
that you maybe didn't know existed in the
first place or maybe you didn't know where
to look for that attack surface because of some
gaps in your knowledge about how the product is
operating or deployed so so i think the number
one mistake that i see from security researchers
that you know we we've hired or just in general is
that they can give up after a short period of time
without actually having uh enough certainty that
they've covered everything inside the application
how much time do you usually spend
before you conclude there are no bugs
around uh one week of full-time time is one
one to two weeks of full-time work sometimes
that's between three people so three people
for one week of full-time is usually a pretty
decent uh indicator if we haven't found anything
after the the one week then we'll we'll probably
look back at that product again in the future what
we'll we'll set up a calendar invite maybe look
at it in a year or something yeah it sounds
like a lot of time especially the only look
at the unauthenticated part which is probably
not even a half of the application most of the
time yeah yeah we are happy to find things post
authentication but every time we find things post
authentication we we usually then spend the rest
of the time looking for an authentication bypass
that's usually okay what we do so if we if we find
stuff that's post-auth it's fine but we will spend
a lot of time looking for an auth bypass what
screams to you this software has a lot of bugs
any any java monolith project anything
that has like you know 20 plus servlets
defined in a web.xml file i'm
sure has something wrong with it
okay when you when you're learning something when
you're learning hacking or specific technology
like you specialize in dotnet after a relatively
short time you get to a point where you can no
longer just find a tutorial in the internet
about something how do you learn it further
i i tend to make c-sharp projects for whatever i'm
looking at so i mean there have been there's been
quite a lot of research um in dotnet that still
is beyond me in many ways like uh for example
uh there's a lot of research from jang that he
recently found an rce in microsoft sharepoint and
um you know there's still stuff like that
in dotnet that's very esoteric and sometimes
difficult to understand and i find that
research the only way to fully understand
it is by setting up some sort of environment
that's similar to what the researcher had and
exploiting that vulnerability step by step now
i haven't had the chance to do that for jang's
vulnerability but i have done this in the past i
have exploited vulnerabilities in the past which
i didn't fully understand and i've written blog
posts about them as well so one of the ones that
really caught my attention was a authentication
bypass vulnerability i think in vmware workspace
one access which i reverse engineered and
recreated to understand it better and wrote
a blog post about so my opinion is just recreate
these vulnerabilities from researchers that you
don't understand so you can actually understand
them do you think for beginners that are just
starting with code review it's the same learning
method or there is something easier for them
um well if you're starting with code review
i i don't think this is something that would
even concern you as much um these the things
that i'm talking about are probably for the the
people that have already done a lot of work
in code review and want to get even better
it's one of those weird things that once you
become good at something you start looking at
the people that are even better than you and
there's such a huge gap between being pretty
good at something and being the best at something
so um yeah i think for people who are beginning uh
there are a ton of code code review exercises on
pentester lab but honestly my my recommendation
still is to look at a real life product that's
being used and auditing that product and that
source code of that product because in
my opinion that's how you learn the most
if you only wanted to prioritize for
earning bug bounty how would you hunt today
uh if i wanted to only earn bug bounty how would i
hunt today um probably a bit of a hybrid approach
so basically what i'm doing right now i mean i'm
still using automation in a lot of my bug bounty
work um but i'm also doing a lot of manual bug
bounty work as well and i'm also doing security
research my recommendation is you split up your
time between those three things and then you do
the rest of the work and that's three things so
manual work uh reconnaissance based automation
and security research okay who do you think
going full-time bug bounty will be good for
i think it would be good for someone that um
has a lifestyle that that doesn't require too
much money to do a lot of work and a lot of things
that you can do to get there um but i think it's a
good thing to do full-time because you're going
to get paid for what you're doing and uh what
you're going to get paid um but at the same time
honestly if you're very good at bug bounties and
you've proven to yourself that you're very
good at it and you make a lot of money then
you're an ideal candidate to go full-time but i
think what a lot of people don't understand that
some of the people getting into the bug bounty
scene might be thinking is oh you know like i
can i can probably do this full-time and make a
ton of money um or whatever but usually all the
people that i've seen who are successful that
are full-time have spent a ridiculous amount
of time um becoming really good at their trade
craft how do you prepare for live hacking events
uh um well i just love collaborating with people
so i just i just hang out with a lot of people
that are similarly passionate about hacking
and we just enjoy hacking things together
it's a pretty fair and easy system everyone
gets splits evenly if they collaborate
and yeah everyone's quite fun to work with i've
just been able to build a really nice network
over the last couple years that we tend to knock
ideas around with each other and we find a lot
of different things that wouldn't have been
possible if we were just working alone so for
preparation for live hacking events i mean i
try my best to just take it easy and not take
it too seriously but at the same time i do try to
prepare well in advance so if i have notification
of a live hacking event i'm spending a ton of time
before the event even starts to to try and find
vulnerabilities that's awesome and you mentioned
collaboration here how do you find people that you
collaborate with completely organically so either
they've reached out to me or i've reached out to
them at some point there are some hackers that i'm
particularly interested in collaborating with that
i've reached out to over the years and have been
able to form really good relationships one of the
things that i will mention about collaboration
is that collaboration is not just the act of
doing some technical work with someone so you can
get paid some amount of money it's about building
real relationships with people and one of the
things that i care about the most in the hacker
community is building real relationships with
you know everyone around me in the bug bounty
space that have not that much to do with any
money or any transactional element or anything
like that i tend to build relationships first
and then choose to collaborate after that after
i've realized that you know such and such person
is a good person i want to i want to spend more
time with them and i think that they're good
at certain things and i will pull them into
collaborations with myself or they will pull
me into collaborations with what they're doing
what do you think people should watch
out for when collaborating with others
um i think one of the one of the things that
you should watch out for is just really knowing
the person that you're collaborating with
before choosing to collaborate with them
because if the person you're collaborating
with has a certain personality that you know
um yeah it can it can go wrong easily if
that person doesn't understand from the
beginning what the splits are if that person
thinks that they're entitled to something more
than what they're entitled to if that person
is maybe jealous or greedy or whatever um it
can be quite tricky to resolve those disputes
and conflicts so before you start working with
someone really try and understand who they are as
a person before you start you know collaborating
technically with them and seeing whether or not
they you know can find stuff for you or with you
um but i don't know i think i i have collaborated
with people time to time that have just randomly
reached out to me but i'm certainly not the type
of person that um you know withholds bounties or
asks for more cut or whatever that may be unless
we both agree on it from the very beginning
okay okay let's now switch to a bit different
topic um you you have an awesome blog at asset
note it's one of the best if not in my
opinion the best source of articles in the
in the industry because you always also share
the process of finding the bugs some technical
tips it's much more than just right off the bat
and the question is why to share your knowledge
and why to disclose your techniques to to the
public yeah i mean the thing is i grew up on
public free content that was out there in the wild
without uh the goodwill nature of everyone in this
world that have that has produced content that
they've put out for the world for them to learn
i wouldn't be here today and i wouldn't have the
privilege that i have to be able to audit this
software and find these vulnerabilities and to
me it's always been about giving back uh to to
this ideology that you know that i'm not afraid
of sharing things i'm not afraid of sharing my
techniques and sharing how i got to some place or
another i think that really if i'm able to educate
people through my content through my words then
that is a success for me and again like one of the
things that our blog posts have been phenomenal
for is really getting the word out there of the
talent and skill that we have at our company and
what we're capable of from a security research
perspective the work that we do is in many ways
uh and it resembles our security research team
and we want to be proud of the work that we put
out there and that's why we spend a lot of time
in actually trying to explain our steps in in how
we found what we did really i think that whoever
is scared of competition and chooses not to share
content because of competition is they themselves
not that competitive because the world i mean if
people really want to learn something they will
learn it and people are going to compete with
you either way if you're really that worried
about competition then and you don't want to share
things then that's fine that's your choice but i
would much rather always be learning and even
if i release things that have a lot of tips or
tricks or whatever i am always looking for our
team and myself to go beyond that the next time
do you sometimes have problems because of
disclosing the vulnerabilities on your blog
post because some sometimes you post the timeline
in the blog post and sometimes you mention some
arguments with the company that maybe they
didn't fix the bug or something like this
yeah it does happen we we have had a few instances
where companies have either refused the bug
refuted the bug or they've either claimed that
what we reported was not real or in many cases
we've also had vendors that just take a lot longer
than the 90-day timeline in order to resolve the
bug as well yeah i mean this is something that is
always a problem with vulnerability and security
research but for us we we tend to be lenient
to the vendor if they have made any sort of
progress so if we know that for a fact the vendor
has you know started working on a fix or has done
some significant work on the fix then we're more
lenient to wait more than the 90 days to release
the the blog post one of the things that i've
noticed as well with a lot of the vulnerabilities
that we find as you know we focus on critical
pre-authentication vulnerabilities almost all
of our vulnerabilities end up being exploited by
threat actors which is you know really something
that that sucks but at the same time we are
following our coordinated disclosure process
we are making sure that the vendors have an ample
amount of time to fix we are not selling any of
our vulnerabilities to zero-day brokers or the
secondary market or the black market or anything
like that where we're pretty much playing this
whole zero-day disclosure game as carefully and
responsibly as we can which you know for us even
though we're doing that we we see our bugs being
picked up by you know threat actors in russia and
china and end up on the caesar most exploited most
known exploited vulnerabilities lists and stuff
like that so it is really tricky you know it is
something that you know we think about quite a
lot but we we really make a good faith effort to
work with the vendor to help them get as many
people patched as possible what are some tips
for people reporting zero days on how to make
the the process as smooth as possible on our
side right yeah absolutely so if you're reporting
any zero-day vulnerabilities if that product that
you're reporting to has a bug bounty program
if you plan to disclose that vulnerability
do not report it through the bug bounty program
absolutely do not because if you report it through
the bug bounty program you are accepting the the
code of conduct and the terms and conditions of
that platform which basically says that you cannot
disclose that vulnerability without explicit
consent from the customer if you want to be
able to disclose your vulnerabilities and you're
finding zero days in whatever it may be and they
have a bug bounty report it via email and when
you report it via email attach a response attach
a coordinated disclosure policy at the top of the
bug report this policy usually goes by something
like you know you have 90 days to fix the issue
or 30 days after patch is when we will release the
blog post so after 90 days or 30 days after patch
we'll release you know an article or blog post or
whatever our advisory that's usually the industry
standard terms for vulnerability disclosure
and these timelines have been solidified by
you know companies like google with project zero
so this is based off that those industry standards
is there maybe a link somewhere
to a policy that that you can
say you can link in the report for for the team
to see or you just say that you will disclose it
in 90 days or 30 days after the patch and that
that's all it is yeah so the policy you know
i mean it's up to you if you have a different
policy you can try and come up with a different
policy but you can just copy the one that's
from google project zero as a starting point
but generally i've also seen some
hackers do something where it's
like you know once the vulnerability is you
know once the vulnerability is remediated we
will publish for example i've seen hackers that
have done things like that as well so it really
depends what you're comfortable with from a policy
perspective but if you're going to be reporting
zero days you need to be attaching these policies
to the top of your vulnerability reports each one
yeah obviously we here we assume that publishing
a blog post is more important for us than getting
a bounty because then you're not getting around
right right so this is definitely assuming that
getting a bounty is less important but a lot
of the hackers that i work with these days
they're not as much interested in the bug bounty
element as they are in the the idea of documenting
their work and publishing their work which is fine
i mean if you're just looking for the bug bounty
that's okay and look there's also a possibility
that if you report it via a bug bounty program
they might still be open for you to publish
your work but that is completely dependent on
them approving the disclosure request yeah yeah
and there are i think few companies that that
we know that always disclose bugs like i don't
know gitlab google and so on but not that many
especially when it's like commercial software yeah
you mentioned here your team a lot what are some
things that you pay attention to when recruiting
security researchers yeah actually one of the
things i've found with a lot of the security
researchers that we've recruited over the last
few years is they have really good skills in ctfs
they've done extremely well playing for ctf teams
and they've also ran ctfs or made challenges
in ctfs that have really caught my attention
so this has been a constant theme with some
of the security researchers that we've hired
but it does require a very specific person to be
interested in what we do and we also have a very
we have a very rigorous technical interview
process for the security researchers that
involves them finding zero days in a number of in
a number of different locations inside the product
how about things like certifications i
don't i don't really look at certifications
i don't look at certifications i don't look
at university degree i don't look at age
either i mainly look at whether or not they are
enthusiastic they know what they're talking about
they understand different elements of source
code analysis and reverse engineering and most
importantly if they can pass a technical take-home
interview how does it look like out of curiosity
uh it's a enterprise product that has several zero
days inside some zero days are much more difficult
to find than others and we give them a week and
they're able to spin up a docker container with
this enterprise software and yeah they have a
week to find as much as they can and uh then they
support their then they send in their report
which is just in markdown we review all of
their findings and um depending on what they've
found they either pass or fail i mean again this
interview is something that's focused primarily
on the pre-auth attack surface um we have had
some cases where people have focused on things
that were post authentication but unfortunately
um you know for this interview we really need
someone to find all the pre-auth stuff there's a
lot of pre-auth stuff and there's varying degrees
of complexity with the vulnerabilities the the
the take-home assessment is not supposed
to be so difficult that you give up but
for us to assess how capable you are it will
depend on whether or not you've discovered
some of the more deeper inherent issues with the
application that are maybe five or six layers deep
within the application so yeah we do assess based
off this technical take-home interview but yeah it
is it is something that we we we heavily rely on
for our security researcher interviews in general
not only for not only for security researchers
but for bug bounty hunters pentesters and pretty
much everyone in security what skills do you think
people should learn to not be replaced by ai soon
um yeah i mean patience um dedication and
persistence some of these skills are not
necessarily things that can be transferred to an
ai i mean you can try and to be honest uh using
ai for security source code review i found that
it often misses things that are a bit tricky or
it hallucinates about things that don't exist so
we're not quite there yet but i'm not uh i'm not
i'm not saying that we won't be there yet i'm
just saying that with the current technologies
that i've been playing around with with ai um
it's not just quite there yet when it comes to
discovering some of the more esoteric complex
vulnerabilities that humans still need to be
involved to discover but yeah i mean really i
think i think that the advice to not be replaced
by ai is the same as what i'd given what i'd
give five years ago which is just focus on what
you're passionate about and become the best at
it as you can possibly be which if it's security
source code auditing they just just become the
best at it as you can possibly be because even
if there's an ai someone will still need to make
sense of those things that that the ai produces
how have you been trying to introduce ai to your
job i've been using it sometimes for engineering
work so i use copilot and i use chat gpt for
different things but i also have been trying
to use it for some vulnerability analysis now it's
not being that good because every time i've done
vulnerability analysis with ai i've found that
it's not always been super accurate at least chat
gpt it's sometimes given me a bunch of leads that
didn't actually have any merit so wasted a bit of
time following those leads and trying to exploit
them or they weren't practical they weren't things
that would be feasible to do even if it was
technically a vulnerability that they weren't
they weren't possible so i'm not quite convinced
yet when it comes to discovering vulnerabilities
with ai but i'm sure that's going to change
within the next 6 to 12 months given how fast
everything is moving how do you think it will look
in five years i think honestly we will be able to
provide a source code repository of some sort and
see all of the different issues that it has and
ideally we'll be able to ask the ai questions
so we'll be able to say how does all the
authentication and authorization work how does all
of the uh what are all of the pre-authentication
routes what are all the post authentication
routes where are all the http clients things
like that but i'm not sure that ai is just quite
there yet for that i think it will be in some time
yeah yeah i think it taking the source code and
asking ai to to list as uh routes available before
authentication should be possible relatively soon
i would say because it seems like a doable job
but i think it will take a long long time so so
ai can actually understand the complex software
especially with like different components and
different code bases it will never completely
replace manual hackers yeah and look like one
of the softwares that we're looking at right
now is like 11 gb um so that's that's huge
uh i don't see us feeding that into a large
language model anytime soon right like there's
there's a lot of complex software out there so
um it will it'll just yeah we'll have to see what
happens yeah yeah yeah yeah i'm very very curious
uh thank you so much for for this interview
but uh before before i let you go what are your
plans for the rest of this year my plans um well
i'll be going to the london live hacking event
um later this year um in june and besides that
i think i'll be going to singapore and a few
other places probably having a new year's party
here in brisbane at the end of the year but yeah
that's that's most of my plans i think when it
comes to hacking and stuff i mean continuing to
write up blog posts and release cool vulnerability
research um for um different enterprise products
so i'm really looking forward to that and yeah
i just progressing asset node i mean we've been
doing this for four and a half years and we're
looking forward to what the future has for us
awesome i definitely cheer cheer you up
for creating the blog posts because they
are really really the best i think source of
learning code code review we'll make sure to
link this for people in the description and
where people go to follow you in social media
uh just twitter twitter's really good um or
linkedin but either one is good i mean i'm on
twitter and i post stuff time to time but yeah
um if you ever have any questions on the source
code review just reach out to me my dms are
open i may not be able to respond to everyone
but i'm happy to help if it's a serious source
code review inquiry something that someone's
actually worked on or has worked through and
has some legitimate question i'm happy to answer
okay thank you so much for
joining today thank you bye
what a fantastic interview here ships mentioned
that for security research he doesn't really
focus on client-side issues but for bug bounty
they can be great and in the last episode of
bug bounty report discussed podcast i interviewed
yusef shimuda who has been top one on bug bounty
facebook's leaderboard for three consecutive
years if you want to hear another episode of
the podcast i recommend you this one for
now thank you for listening and goodbye!